Emil Reji

Profile

I'm a full stack Software Engineer based in the Greater New York City Area. I am a co-creator of Stagehand Framework, a drop-in service for automatically deploying and managing review apps for front end applications. I have experience in a variety of technologies including, but not limited to the Ruby and JavaScript Ecosystems. I've worked on agile development teams and can build applications using AWS while using industry standard tooling like Git, GitHub, and Docker.

Professional Experience

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Stagehand-Framework

08/2020 - present

https://stagehand-framework.github.io/ ☑

- Researched a variety of topics for Stagehand including common web app architectures, AWS resources, generic application build processes, static site generators, common client side APIs, and much more
- Designed and implemented the AWS infrastructure using a Cloudfront CDN, IAM Permissions, Cloudformation Automation, Lambda@Edge Functions, and EC2 Instances
- Used Github Actions to automate review app creation and tear down in response to Github events
- Used service workers and other client side code to implement a dashboard for the review app users while simultaneously solving our complex routing issues
- Created an npm package to provide a simple CLI that pulls together Stagehand's architecture
- Co-authored Stagehand's case study □
- Collaborated daily with the rest of Stagehand's remote team

Software Engineer, Senior Associate, Infosys

09/2018 - 08/2020

- Worked as a tester and a developer with the following technologies: Java, Spring, Oracle, SQL, Python, Angular, Jenkins, Agile, etc.
- Was selected as part of Infosys's #FlyingHigh Associate Success Stories
- Gained extensive experience working remotely across multiple time zones world wide

Education

Bachelors of Science in IT, Minor in Computer Science,

2014 - 2018

Montclair State University

GPA of 3.725 on a 4.0 scale

Information Security Certificate,

2016 - 2017

County College of Morris

Skills

Back End

Node.js, Express, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, SQL, MongoDB, REST API's, GraphQL, Webhooks, Java

Front End

JavaScript (ES6), React, Redux, HTML/CSS, Gatsby, Next.js, jQuery

Cloud

AWS, Digital Ocean, Heroku, Vercel

Tooling/Other

Git/Github, Docker, Jenkins, Agile Development